

Rubén Puerta

Full Stack Developer

Contact

@ ruben@puertacordoba.com

puertacordoba.com

/rpuertaco

in /in/rubenpuerta

Tech Skills

Languages: TypeScript, Kotlin, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Java.

Frameworks & Libraries: Angular, Spring Boot, Express.js, NodeJS, Primeng, TailwindCSS, Bootstrap.

Databases: PostgreSQL, MSSQL,

MongoDB.

Tools & Others: Git, WebSockets, AWS

(S3), Sass.

Languages

Spanish - Native

Catalan - Native

English - Fluent (C1)

French - Advanced (B2)

Slovak - Basic (A2)

Certifications

Web Developer Bootcamp

Visit my website to discover more

Professional Summary

I am an enthusiastic full stack developer with years of experience building web applications using technologies like TypeScript, JavaScript, Angular, Spring Boots, Kotlin, and SQL databases. Passionate about optimizing performance and user experience, with a strong focus on both frontend and backend development. Furthermore, I enjoy updating myself and keeping myself up to date on this everevolving industry

Work Experience

Full Stack Developer - Lenovo (August 2022 - Present)

Developed an application for global supply chain using Angular for frontend, Spring Boot (Kotlin) for backend with AWS S3, SAML 2.0 and PostgreSQL database.

Migrated, updated and translated a legacy Java application to Kotlin, optimizing performance, code maintainability and adding new features and changes.

Worked with SQL databases (PostgreSQL, MicrosoftSQL).

Updated and maintained legacy web applications in many other languages, including PHP, enhancing functionality and resolving performance bottlenecks.

Advertising Specialist - Amazon (January 2021 - July 2022)

Customer Service Specialist - Booking.com (April 2016 - August 2020)

Education

Master's in Web App and Website Development - Universitat Oberta de Catalunya (2020 - 2022)

Bachelor's in Tourism - Universitat de Girona (2011 - 2015)

Projects

Gastrolinked - Web app for restaurant order management in real time using websockets.

Technologies: Angular, Express.js, MongoDB, Websockets.

Master's thesis

Templateasy (Available for Firefox and Chrome) - Template management tool to store templates in the browser.

Technologies: JavaScript, HTML/CSS.

This app was used at Amazon Advertising.

View in Chrome Firefox

Band Site Website mockup - Responsive mockup website for a music band.

Technologies: Stylelint, Sass.

Website